A Guide to the Constituent Correspondence of Governor Timothy M. Kaine, 2001-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Governor Timothy M. Kaine, Constituent Correspondence, 2001-2010 (bulk 2006-2009)
The Library of Virginia
44678
90 cu. ft. (90 boxes)
Governor Timothy M. Kaine
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Before serving the materials, Library reference archivists must check the files for privacy protected and confidential information.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, Accession 44678 transferred on 13 January 2010.
Biographical Information
Timothy Kaine was elected 70th governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia in November 2005 and inaugurated on 14 January 2006. He served until 16 January 2010.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, 2001-2010 (bulk 2006-2009), from constituents of Governor Timothy Kaine, including requests for assistance and inquiries about the Governor's stance on certain policy issues. Also included are letters from federal and state agencies, local government officials, Virginia General Assembly members, members of the U.S. Congress, and others, including the U.S. President, governors of other states and ambassadors. The Kaine administration was dominated by three issues: budget deficits, transportation funding and the 16 April 2007 shootings at Virginia Tech.
Starting in late 2007, Constituent Services started using IQ, a proprietary system of Lockheed-Martin, to track correspondence. The correspondence is arranged numerically by IQ number, which is mostly chronological. Since the scanners were slowly rolled out and not every letter was scanned, Constituent Services sent the paper and electronic versions.
A sampling of the mass mailings were kept and include letters related to particular subjects such as the execution of Percy Levar Walton and Dexter Lee Vinson, mercury pollution, juvenile probation officers, trash imports, fishing, interstate waste, mountain top removal, Mattaponi River protection, offshore drilling, protection of Chesapeake Bay, prayer in school, second hand smoke, disabilty rights, coal, and others.
Included are some constituent correspondence left over from Governor Mark Warner's term 2002-2006. Also included are papers relating to the Governor's Fellows and Intern Program and Proclamations and Certificates of Recognition. Throughout and also at the end of the collection are boxes with various IQ numbers for a range of time that were not interfiled.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by IQ number, with miscellaneous materials arranged to the rear. RESEARCHERS SHOULD PAY SPECIAL ATTENTION to the box numbers as they are not in box number order [box numbers were kept as originally numbered]. There is also some overlap among boxes so several boxes may need to be examined.
Contents List
- Governor Mark Warner constituent correspondence, 2001 November-2002 January (Box 1)
- Governor Mark Warner constituent correspondence, 2001 November-2002 January (Box 7)
- Governor-elect Timothy Kaine constituent correspondence, Mass mailings, 2005 November-December (Box 160)
- Governor-elect Timothy Kaine constituent correspondence, Miscellaneous, 2005 November-December (Box 161)
- 2567500-2569999, 2006 January (Box 8)
- 2568154-2588759, 2006 January-April (Box 8a)
- 2570000-2573099, 2006 January (Box 9)
- 2573100-2575199, 2006 February-March (Box 10)
- 2575200-2578299, 2006 February-March (Box 11)
- 2579300-2584599, 2006 March (Box 12)
- 2584600-2589399, 2006 March-April (Box 13)
- 2589400-2593499, 2006 April (Box 14)
- 2593500-2596899, 2006 April-May (Box 15)
- 2596900-2600099, 2006 May-June (Box 16)
- 2600102-2604999, 2006 May-June (Box 22)
- 2605000-2608898, 2006 June-July (Box 23)
- 2608900-2612200, 2006 July-August (Box 41)
- 2612300-2616999, 2006 August-September (Box 32)
- 2617000-2619899, 2006 August-September (Box 31)
- 2619900-2623099, 2006 September-October (Box 36)
- 2623100-2625699, 2006 October-November (Box 33)
- 2620000-2647499 [various], 2006 October-2007 February (Box 46)
- 2625700-2628999, 2006 November-December (Box 40)
- 2629000-2631499, 2006 November-December (Box 35)
- 2631500-2634299, 2006 December-2007 January (Box 51)
- Various numbers, 2006-2007 (Box 166)
- 2634300-2636399, 2007 January (Box 55)
- 2636400-2638999, 2007 January (Box 57)
- 2639100-2643099, 2007 January-February (Box 58)
- 2643100-2645299, 2007 January-February (Box 58)
- 2645300-2648999, 2007 January-February (Box 54)
- 2649000-2653099, 2007 February-March (Box 52)
- 2647500-2659999 [various], 2007 February-March (Box 48)
- 2653100-2658199, 2007 March (Box 53)
- 2658200-2661999, 2007 March (Box 61)
- 2662000-2664399, 2007 March-April (Box 67)
- 2672400-2731600 [various], 2007 March-June (Box 43)
- 2664400-2666999, 2007 April (Box 66)
- 2667000-2669999, 2007 April-May (Box 65)
- 2670000-2671599, 2007 May (Box 64)
- 2671600-2673999, 2007 May (Box 64a)
- 2674000-2677799, 2007 May-June (Box 63)
- 2677800-2680999, 2007 June-July (Box 68)
- 2681100-2684499, 2007 July (Box 69)
- 2684500-2688399, 2007 July-August (Box 70)
- 2688400-2691799, 2007 August (Box 73)
- 2691800-2694099, 2007 August-September (Box 74)
- 2694100-2698399, 2007 September-October (Box 78)
- 2698400-2701999, 2007 October (Box 75)
- 2702000-2709899, 2007 October-November (Box 77)
- 2710000-2713599, 2007 December (Box 139)
- 2713600-2719999, 2007 December-2008 January (Box 81)
- Various numbers, 2007 (Box 158)
- 2720000-2728999, 2008 January-February (Box 85)
- 2730100-2737099, 2008 March (Box 90)
- 2737100-2741499, 2008 March-April (Box 92)
- 2741500-2746199, 2008 April-May (Box 98)
- 2746200-2751499, 2008 May-June (Box 99)
- 2751500-2757199, 2008 June-July (Box 107)
- 2757200-2760699, 2008 July (Box 101)
- 2760700-2763999, 2008 July-August (Box 103)
- 2764000-2769999, 2008 August-September (Box 105)
- 2770000-2778099, 2008 September-October (Box 109)
- 2778200-2783599, 2008 October-November (Box 110)
- 2783600-2790499, 2008 November-December (Box 115)
- 2790600-2795499, 2008 December-2009 January (Box 116)
- 2795500-2799799, 2008 December-2009 January (Box 118)
- Various numbers, 2008 (Box 154)
- Various numbers, 2008-2009 (Box 91)
- Various numbers, 2008-2009 (Box 153)
- Various numbers, 2008-2009 (Box 157)
- Various numbers, 2008-2009 (Box 159)
- 2799800-2811199, 2009 January-February (Box 120)
- 2811200-2819099, 2009 February-March (Box 123)
- 2819100-2827599, 2009 March-April (Box 127)
- 2827600-2830899, 2009 March-April (Box 128)
- 2830900-2835199, 2009 April-May (Box 135)
- 2835200-2840899, 2009 June (Box 137)
- 2841000-2846599, 2009 June-July (Box 138)
- 2847000-2852099, 2009 July (Box 140)
- 2852100-2856099, 2009 August-September (Box 142)
- 2856100-2862999, 2009 September-October (Box 143)
- 2863000-2870399, 2009 October-December (Box 145)
- 2870700-2874699, 2009 November-December (Box 147)
- Various numbers, 2009-2010 (Box 155)
- Mass mailings, 2006-2009 (Box 2)
- Governor's Fellows and Intern Program, 2006-2009 (Box 162)
- Archiving, 2008 (Box 152)
- FOIA, 2009 (Box 152)
- Military deaths, 2007-2009 (Box 152)
- Proclamations and Certificates of Recognition, 2008-2009 (Box 152)
- Virginia Tech letters of condolence to Governor, 2007 (Box 152)
- Reaffirmation of the Importance of an Act Establishing Religious Freedom in the World Today, from the Consortium for Richmond's Religious History, 2008 January (Box 167)